Hello friends, how are you all? I am your
friend MK. Today I have brought a very
exciting video for you. Today the
topic of our video is debt is the
care procedure. What happens
in health insurance,
procedures for which we
need hospitalization for treatment, but
sir, our treatment is done within 24 hours.
Debt management is C-Gate
treatment within 24 hours of admission in
hospital and CR discharge within 24
hours. Now friends, this question must be coming in your mind
that what
procedures are covered in medical or
health and insurance policy,
sir, is it covered, its coverage is available, it was
not available earlier, but there was
advancement
in medical facilities, medical science became so advanced,
its cost factor increased so much that the
Debt
Issuerence Regulatory and Development
Authority of India, which is the main governing body of our country which governs the insurance industry, took the initiative in this and
told all the insurance companies that sir,
you have to provide coverage to debt care procedures as well in the
policy, then all the companies started considering this.  It has also
started giving coverage. We will talk about
some such procedures on which
it applies close to DK procedure
and whose treatment is done within 24 hours,
but this is a very expensive treatment. If
we talk about
cancer treatment, for any type
of cancer, chemotherapy is given.
Chemotherapy treatment is given and
chemotherapy is done within
24 hours. It is done within these 24
hours. You go to the hospitals for this
and within 24 hours you go back to your home. Firstly,
this cancer related
chemotherapy is done, after that kidney related
treatment, dialysis, that
dialysis process is also done within 24 hours, it is a
very expensive procedure,
you get coverage for this also
under the Dekar procedure. Then the
treatment of caterect, Moti Arvind,
any such treatment which is retina related, I will
not go into the technicalities too much, let's stick to the
basics. If the
eyesight gets reduced, then there are some certain
treatments for which you need 24-
hour hospital treatment.  It has to be done and
sir, your wish is fulfilled,
like
[music]
biopsy is
required for investigation of cancer
and its treatment is also done, that
also comes under de-care procedure, biopsy is done,
endoscopy is done, then
for infinitums also, everything is yours under 24 hours,
now let's talk about why insurance companies
started covering this, we had
told you earlier that Insurance
Regulatory Development Authority of India took the
initiative, seeing that all these
procedures have become very expensive and since then
insurance companies started
giving coverage for it in their products, in their policies, these
de-care procedures, these
account for a
major percentage
of their expense, it goes in de-
care procedures, if you see, if
you go for any treatment, then the treatment of de-care
treatment, de-care procedure, it
forms a
major trunk of your overall treatment of your own
health expenditure, so that's why
sir, this is covered by medical insurance mediclaim
company  has started assuring this also
and when you take a policy, then
you must keep in mind that the
care procedures are
covered or not under your policy, if there is coverage then what are the
care procedures covered in it, to get
clarification on this thing,
understand every aspect of every thing from your company so that if
ever you need treatment related to the care procedure, then
your company
stands behind you to give you backup
and you do not have to spend money from your pocket,
so friends this was a small basic
video on care procedures, I hope
you all liked it, if you liked it then
like, share, subscribe and
give a thumbs up to my channel and take
good care of yourself till the day is over. Bye